Finding Aid for the Olive Percival Papers LSC.0119
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 4. Manuscripts., (including typescripts)
  - Japanese poems; third book., Item 18 (Box 5)
    Cover inscribed with title and name. One poem copied on each sheet of double paper, Japanese style, reading from back to front; mounted in paper cover, book form. [64] double 1. 22cm.
  - My hats and bonnets of the/yester years., Item 19 (Box 5)
    Typed list, three sheets (8 1/2 × 13), entitled "My Hats and Bonnets of the Yester Years." Pencil notations.
  - Old fashioned flower gardens., Item 20 (Box 5)
    Typescript, six sheets (8 1/2 × 13), entitled "Old-Fashioned Flower-Gardens." Signed, ink, by Olive Percival, at bottom page 6.
  - Regina O'Kane., Item 21 (Box 5)
    Typescript, three sheets (8 1/2 × 13), entitled "Regina O'Kane," written by Olive Percival after the death of Miss O'Kane. First page carbon, p. 2 and 3 originals. Pencil note on back of p.3: "Times/Exp. 7/20."
  - Sugarplums., Item 22 (Box 5)
    Typescript, six sheets (8 1/2 × 13), entitled "Sugarplums." Signed, ink, by Olive Percival on page 6.
  - To remember., Item 23 (Box 5)
    Typescript (carbon), one sheet (8 1/2 × 8 1/2), poem entitled "To Remember," 7 stanzas, 4 lines each. At bottom left, ink, OP has written: "Copy For dearest A. K. - Olive Percival."
  - To remember., Item 24 (Box 5)
    Typescript (carbon), one sheet (8 1/2 × 11), poem entitled "To Remember," 7 stanzas, 4 lines each. At bottom, ink, OP has listed persons' names under words "Copy" and "Programme."
  - Where are the bonnets of yester year?, Item 25 (Box 5)
    Typescript, seven sheets (8 1/2 × 11), entitled "Where are the Bonnets of Yester Year?" Consists of random paragraphs and notes apparently collected from an article under this title.
  - William Vaughn Moody., Item 26 (Box 5)
    Typescript, three sheets (8 1/2 × 11), entitled "William Vaughn Moody. His Personality." On back of p.3, ink, by OP: "William Vaughn Moody."
  - A Word about Japanese ceramics., Item 27 (Box 5)
    Typescript, six sheets (8 1/2 × 13), entitled "A Word About Japanese Ceramics," signed on p.6, ink, by Olive Percival. Page 5 original, others blue carbon. Note by OP, ink, upper right p.1: "1st/(Ten Minute Paper Read by Mrs. Stilson/Ruskin Art Club. Then I read: April 1909)." Back of p.6, ink: "Japanese Ceramics 1909."
  - "To Remember", Item 28 (Box 5)
    (Gift of Mrs. Florence Kreider, 1949) Typescript of poem "To Remember" (carbon copy) - seven stanzas of four lines. 1 thin sheet. At lower left, written in ink by OP: "For dearest Polly-/8 May-/1934/Olive Percival."
    See also 119/4/23-24.
  - "Our Old-Fashioned Flowers", Item 29 (Box 5)
    Typescript of article "Our Old-Fashioned Flowers" (carbon copy).
    120 sheets 8-1/2 × 13 Thin white.
    Bound in brown paper cover with white label on cover bearing ink inscription in OP's hand: "Our/Old-fashioned/Flowers-/Olive/Percival"
    Two printed sheets laid in (proof sheets?) entitled "Pot herbs, sallet herbs, stewing herbs, and simples. A short list."
    Gift of Ward Ritchie. February, 1950.
  - Some Japanese Poems., Item 30 (Box 5)
    Manuscript, in ink, entitled "Some Japanese Poems/Copied/For/Florence Moore/1912/By Olive/Percival" (inscribed on cover).
    One poem copied on each sheet of double paper, Japanese style, reading from back to front; mounted in paper cover, book form. 21.5cm.
    Gift of Mrs. Kreider, July 1950.
- 5. Personal notes.
  - 61 cards and scraps of paper, Item 1 (Box 5)
    61 cards and scraps of paper with notations, ink with pencil additions, by OP: names of persons in whom she was interested, sometimes noting addresses, or places where she met them, with her impressions of them.
    J. T. Armstrong
    Ernest A. Bachelder
    Carrie Jacobs Bond
    Elizabeth Putnam Borglum
    Ira H. Brainerd
    Rachel Burer
    Lillian Burkhardt (Goldsmith)
    Sheldon Cheney
    Samuel Travers Clover
    Madge Witt Clover
    Helen E. Coan
    Constance Crawley
    May Curran
    Natalie Curtis
    Elizabeth B. Custer
    Eva Porter Daggett
    Miss Lucutta Daniel
    Irving Day
    Estelle C. Heartt (Dreyfuss)
    Edwin Emerson, Jr.
    Emma Newman Emerson
    Paul England
    Lucine Finch
    Mrs. A.S.C. Forbes
    Mrs. E. F. Foster
    Mrs. E. M. Fowler
    Elbridge M. Fowler
    Mary E. Foy
    Don Carlos de la Guerra
    Hilda Hasse
    Anna Held Heinrich
    Harriet Hutchcraft Hill
    Mrs. Bertha E. Jacques
    Miss Elizabeth L. Kenney
    Mary Holland Kincaid
    Alice Klauber
    Lillian Corbett Barnes Long
    M. Fay Loughlin
    Charles F. Lummis
    Eve Douglas (Mrs. C.F.Lummis no.2)
    Henrietta Whipple Lungren
    Fernand Lungren
    Margaret Lucie Mabury
    Amanda Mathews
    Clara MacChesney
    Olive Thorne Miller
    Lucy Monroe
    Ethel Moore
    Dorothea Moore
    Yet C. Owyang
    Anne Partlan
    Mrs. George Whitworth Pursell (Nona [UNK]
    Irving B. Richman
    Kathryn Rucker (Luelin)
    Morgan Shephard
    Lu Wheat (Smith)
    Alice & Amy Smith
    Ethel Stewart
    Wilbur Macey Stone
    Idah Meacham Strobridge
    Mrs. Enoch R. Vedder
    Julia Bracken (Wendt)
    William Wendt
    Alma Whitaker
  - 20 names and addresses torn from envelopes:, Item 2 (Box 5)
    Mrs. Everard Bierer
    Mrs. Charles W. Boyden
    Mildred Bryant Brooks
    Mrs. L. B. Crandall
    E. S. Dessau (former teacher) - See Essay on Christopher Columbus 119/4/11
    E. Hamilton Fairley
    L. Fogle
    Annie F. Foss
    Mrs. Fred E. Hancock
    Mrs. Ida H. Holloway
    Alice Klauber (see note among/1)
    Grace P. Ormsby
    Mrs. A. G. Palfrey
    Mrs. E. Sparling
    Mrs. C. F. Saunders
    W. O. Ryan
    Mrs. George N. Wadleigh (written by OP)
    Mrs. Louis Ward Watkins
    Lila Williams
    Mrs. Frederick C. Williams.
  - Envelope addressed to OP bears her pencil notations, "Old-Fashioned Sugar-Meats" - "Write Book: Sugar-plums" - "Notes for Sugar Plums.", Item 3 (Box 5)
    It contains 6 scraps of paper upon which Miss Percival has scribbled notes in combined long hand and short hand, and a newspaper clipping "Penny Candies not Hoarded" noted with the date, 1932.
  - Envelope noted in ink by Miss Percival, "O.P./ Memories/ Child Memories", Item 4 (Box 5)
    Containing: typewritten list of events from her birthdate until Jan. 14, 1874, with notations in ink; original and carbon of typed sheet listing items plus notations mentioned in foregoing item; part of letterhead with pencil notes on back; a strip of typewritten paper (carbon) with her memories of an Ohio village.
  - Duplicate draft for $50.00 drawn on the Hongkong & Shanghai Banking Corporation, payable to Miss M. F. Denton., dated Feb. 27, 1903; Item 5 (Box 5)
    On the back of the draft Miss Percival has written, in pencil: "She never acknowledged this - nor bought me the books with it. But put it in a fund for a girl sent to a German University, where she got a degree - In 1918, Miss D. in L.A. referred to this girl as having married well and, having two motorcars! And said "That's the Japanese girl you helped educate!" etc.
  - Printed manila card, written in ink on back, dimensions of rooms of house., Item 6 (Box 5)
  - Green Christmas card, dimensions of rooms, etc., noted, ink, on back., Item 6 (Box 5)
  - White Christmas card, noted both sides, ink: "The Down-hyl Claim,", with dimensions of various rooms, dated 5/1923.; Item 6 (Box 5)
  - Printed card, back noted in ink: "1922 / The Down-hyl Claim / 551 ft. of book shelves., Item 7 (Box 5)
    For present number of Books I need more than 1000' × New house should have 1500 ft. (in pencil) or more (1935, nearly 10,000 bks.)"
  - Scrap of white paper noted in ink:, Item 8 (Box 5)
    "I found this pretty new coin on the n/w cor. of our place March 26/1898 - when we were thinking of buying in the Arroyo. A beautiful spring day."
  - Eight Beauties of Omi, Item 9; Small piece of yellow paper, noted in ink: (Box 5)
    Autumn Moon at Omi
    Snow at Evening
    Sunset
    Evening Bell of the Temple
    Clear Sky
    Wild Geese going North
    Rainy Night
    Returning Boat
    Pilgrimages made to see these 8 Beauties - No cultured Japanese willing to die unless accomplished.
  - The Five Most Picturesque Towns of Europe, Item 10; Small piece of white paper with decorative cut-out at top, noted, ink: (Box 5)
    Le Puy
    Mont-St.-Michel
    Carcassonne
    San Cimignano
    Rothenburg.
  - Piece of white paper with top cut out in shape of large jar and folded down over itself., Item 11 (Box 5)
    Written on outside, "A Pot Pourri of Roses"; on inside, "The First of my Annual Pot Pourris (of Roses) made in 1902 - The Garden was then three years old. The Down-Hyl Claim." Listed below the names of 22 women and 2 men.
  - "Fine Old Houses / Salem / Newburyport / Portsmouth, N.H. / Wiscasset, Me.", Item 12; Small piece of white paper cut out in spade-shape, noted; ink (Box 5)
  - "Hearts-and Hand Valentines Made and Sent to", Item 13 (Box 5)
    List of 22 names written by OP, ink, on sheet of white letter paper entitled "Hearts-and Hand Valentines Made and Sent to"; sheet decorated at bottom with design of basket and flowers and dated "St. Valentine's Day 1932."
  - "Gardening Duties /, 1 February 1911."; Item 14 (Box 5)
    List written by OP, ink, on back of a Christmas greeting, entitled "Gardening Duties / 1 February 1911."
  - "Garden Promises /, July 1928."; Item 14 (Box 5)
    List written by OP, ink, on plain blue card, entitled "Garden Promises / July 1928."
  - "Favorite Declamations in Father's Schooldays, c. 1850."; Item 15 (Box 5)
    List written by OP, ink, on small piece of blue note paper, entitled "Favorite Declamations in Father's Schooldays, c. 1850."
  - "To Remember When I am Blind!", Item 16 (Box 5)
    List written by OP, ink, on large invitation folder, entitled "To Remember When I am Blind!"
  - 4 lists written by OP, Item 17; ink, on sheets of various sizes, folded: (Box 5)
    - "Summer Evenings /, 1925."
    - "Things to Do /, 21 Jany. 1929."
    - "Things I must do during the, Winter of 1930-31."
    - "To Do", n.d.; (on gray paper)
  - What I best Loved & Remember / The May Morris Exhibit / N.Y., February 1910 /; Item 18 (Box 5)
    List written by OP, ink, on thin white paper with one end cut in bell shape and folded over, with caption "What I best Loved & Remember / The May Morris Exhibit / N.Y., February 1910 / With Margaret Fowles."
  - "Bedside Books", Item 19 (Box 5)
    List written by OP, ink, entitled "Bedside Books"- folded note paper.
  - "Names for Bags to be made and sold by the Pasadena Red Cross Street Shops., 2 June, 1918."; Item 20 (Box 5)
    List typed on sheet (8 1/2 × 13), entitled "Names for Bags to be made and sold by the Pasadena Red Cross Street Shops. 2 June, 1918."
  - List, Item 21 (Box 5)
    List typed on white sheet (8 1/2 × 11). At top: "O, why did not the flower-namers call some of our lovely flowers such names as / Cheerful Children / Springday Clouds / Princes-in-The-Tower / Danty Dolls..." etc.
  - Acceptance form from Editor of Life, Item 22 (Box 5)
    pasted inside folded sheet of gray note paper. OP has written, ink, on outside: "My First Acceptance / `Life' / Lines (to Stephen Crane) 1896 / $1.50 / Wonder How I spent it!"
  - "Books consulted.", Item 23 (Box 5)
    Typed list (carbon) on single sheet (8 1/2 × 11) entitled "Books consulted." Books listed pertain to Colonial homesteads and gardens.
  - 2 fragments of paper, Item 24 (Box 5)
    with comments, apparently regarding OP's poems; one a carbon on pink paper, the other typed in blue on white paper.
  - Place card, Item 25 (Box 5)
    ink: Miss Percival. Inside note, ink: "With my love/ Swami Parbhavananda;" and, ink, written by OP: "Carrie Weed Wyckoff 80/ Ida Meed Herman 82/Birthday Dinner/22 March-1939/1946 Iver St.- Hollywood"/ [under the Swami's name] "(Sat next me) Seventeen at Table."
  - Japan Society, Item 26 (Box 5)
    Printed card for lecture of Japan Society, noted, ink, by OP on back: Monograms achieved. List of 12 follows.
  - Birthdays, 1940.; Item 27 (Box 5)
    List written on two sheets thin white paper, ink, by OP: Birthdays 1940. 42 names, with gifts given, listed.
  - "Cover Designs by George Plank.", Item 28 (Box 5)
    Typed list (carbon) - 2 different versions - of "Cover Designs by George Plank." Each sheet bears a note in OP's hand.
    Miscellaneous 119/12/7 Lists of Books
- 6. Christmas Lists
  - Lists, Items 1 - 35 (Box 2)
    written by OP, ink, consisting of several pages for each year (1892-1895, 1897-1916, 1918-1928), stapled or pinned together. The lists comprise names of persons, and gift or card sent to each. The list for 1920 contains 508 names.
- 7. Guest Books.
  - Book covered with worn Japanese gilt paper brocade., Item 1 (Box 5)
    Title page decorated in water color and noted by OP, ink: "The Down-hyl Claim/The Gueste Booke of Mistresse Olive Percival, Spinster/Who abides near the faire cittie of Los Angeles & in the goodlie Province of California." Last signatures dated 1909. 25.5 × 22 cm.
  - Book covered with worn Japanese gilt paper brocade., Item 2 (Box 5)
    Title page decorated in water color and noted by OP in ink: "Mistresse Olive Percival, Spinster/Her Guest Booke/The Down-hyl Claim, Los Angeles." Following page also decorated, initialed "OP" and dated (ink) 10/1910. Last entries in book dated 1936. 11.5 × 9.25 cm.
- 8. Scrap books.
  - Book covered with green leather stamped with a gold design. Contains clippings from newspapers and magazines re: OP's writings. 8 × 5.25cm., Item 1 (Box 5)
  - Smiles., Item 2 (Box 3)
    Humorous poems, clipped and mounted in a small book (a few typed copies are included) with yellow paper cover.
    Title composed of ink dots in the form of "SMILES"; OP in ink dots; on cover.
    Book made and decorated by OP. 11.5 cm.
  - Little Songs., Item 3 (Box 3)
    Poems clipped and mounted in hand made book with green paper cover. Manuscript copy, ink, of anonymous poem on first page. 24 clipped, unmounted poems laid in pages. Title "Little Songs" and initials "OP" formed of dots of ink on front cover. 17 cm.
  - Book with initials E-V-D, Item 4 (Box 3)
    Book made of thin yellow paper sheets in blue cover which has initials "E-V-D" formed of ink dots on the front. A number of poems have been clipped and mounted in the book. 17.5 cm.
  - "Gardens" and "OP", Item 5 (Box 3)
    Book made of white paper with black and white paper cover, with title "Gardens" and "OP" in ink on spine. Filled with clipped poems, typed poems, one manuscript poem. Many of the poems are dated in pencil, ink, by OP. Book contains OP's bookplate (designed by George Plank) inside front cover. 20 cm.
  - "Another/, 1937"; Item 6 (Box 3)
    Book made of white paper with brown and white paper cover, bearing title "Another/1937" and initials "OP" in design of ink dots on front. Contains poems, clipped and mounted, some copied in ink, many are dated in ink or pencil. 23 cm.
    Note: Items 2 through 6 gift of Mrs. Kreider July 1950 - contained in box with label "Books /OP /fecit"
- 9. Memorandum book of purchases, engagement books, diaries, etc.
  - Black leather notebook. Written in ink by OP, notations of objects purchased, and prices, 1905 - 1933.; Item 1; 12.5 × 8 cm. (Box 5)
  - Engagement book, 1910.; Item 2 (Box 5)
    Black, leather, gold stamped "Engagements" on cover. Gift of Mrs. Kirby, Sept. 1949.
- 10. Affiliations, Subscriptions, Contributions.
  - The American Society of Colonial Families., Item 1 (Box 2)
    Receipt to OP dated May 31, 1917 for yearly membership dues of $1.50, and a fifty cent subscription to The Colonial.
  - Animal Defense
    see Permanent Subscriptions.
  - Antiques
  - The Caroline Scott Harrison Memorial., Item 2 (Box 2)
    Receipt to OP dated June 17, 1924 for contribution of $1.00 to the Caroline Scott Harrison Memorial fund (Daughters of the American Revolution).
  - Daughters of the American Revolution
  - Etchers' Society
  - [Foreign relief donations], Item 3 (Box 2)
    Notations in pencil on sheet of white paper, donations to war relief organizations. No date on sheet.
  - The Friday Morning Club., Item 4 (Box 2)
    3 monthly programs of the Friday Morning Club, for February, April, and May, 1911. OP appears on the Programme Committee in charge of Art.
    see also Permanent Subscriptions.
  - The International Longfellow Society., Item 5 (Box 2)
    Card no.4712 issued to OP as a life member.
  - Japan Society, London
  - Japanese Relief Committee for Southern California., Item 6 (Box 2)
    Receipt to OP dated Sept. 5, 1923 for contribution of $25.00.
  - National Society of Daughters of the American Revolution
    see National Society of Mayflower Descendants.
  - National Society of Mayflower Descendants., Item 7 (Box 2)
    Addresses, ink, (not OP's handwriting) on sheet of paper torn from a calendar: Society of Mayflower Descendants on one side, D.A.R. on the other.
  - [Permanent Subscriptions], Item 8 (Box 2)
    Written on back of printed white card, nine organizations with annual subscriptions. Dated 12/1/25, with shorthand notes and other notations in pencil.
  - Plymouth Memorial Fund
    see Society of Mayflower Descendants in the State of California.
  - Psychopathic Parole Society., Item 9 (Box 2)
    Receipt dated Feb. 1927 for contribution of $25.00 to Psycopathic Parole Society, Resthaven Building Fund.
  - Seamen's Church Institute of San Francisco., Item 10 (Box 2)
    Receipt dated Oct. 3, 1918 for donation of $1.00.
  - Society for Prevention of Cruelty to Animals
    see Permanent Subscription
  - Society of Mayflower Descendants in the State of California., Item 11 (Box 2)
    Three receipts, all dated June 1921, for various fees.
  - Society of Mayflower Descendants in the State of California., Item 12 (Box 2)
    Roster of membership, 1939. Bears OP's signature, ink, on front cover. Laid in back, Bulletin No.238 of the Society.
  - Sulgrave Manor Endowment Fund., Item 13 (Box 2)
    Receipt dated Jan.14, 1923 for contribution of $5.00 to Sulgrave Manor Endowment Fund, National Society of the Colonial Dames of America.
  - Vanity Fair
- 12. Miscellaneous
  - Envelope, Item 1 (Box 6)
    (3 × 6 cm.) made of gold paper containing folded note paper, with note written by OP, ink, signed "The Queen of Hearts" dated "The Purple Palace / February 39th."
  - 3 paper cut-outs: leaf, flowering pea, girl seated in chair., Item 2 (Box 6)
  - Card, Item 3 (Box 6)
    with apple blossoms painted in water color on one side; on the other in ink "For Mary's Birthday." OP's pencil note at top" (Aunt P.Lynn, Mass.)
    [Missing as of 6-28-1982.]
  - [Miscellaneous], Item 4 (Box 6)
    Bits of paper and cloth, a small white envelope marked "OP Rags" and noted by OP, pencil, "Fr W.M.S.", and fold of pink note paper noted, ink, "Fragments Early 19th c. see pages 21,22,23 / From Wilbur Macey Stone." [See photograph of Wilbur Macey Stone with "Pictures-Unframed" and item 119/3/5.]
  - Pressed leaves (4) and flower (1)., Item 5 (Box 6)
  - Catalogue: Paul J. Howard's California Flowerland., Item 6 (Box 6)
    Contains full size illustration in color of the Olive Percival rose. (Added to collection 11/3/48.) 29 cm. 8 l.
  - White cardboard stationery box, Item 7 (Box 6)
    (9.5×6.5×1.5") with two OP markers pasted on top, and the work "McGuffey." printed in ink on top and on two sides, containing the following material [Gift of Ward Ritchie, January 5, 1959]:
    - Letter addressed to "Dear Miss Percival", signed "Jessie S. Crook" Denver., dated Nov. 20th (1930); Written on card, with cover.
    - List written in ink by OP on note paper, entitled "My Shelf of Old Readers:, 1920"
    - List written in ink by OP on folded note paper, entitled "My Shelf of Old Readers, 22 Feb. 1922"
    - 3 clippings from book lists re McGuffey Readers, dated in pencil by OP 3-40, respectively., 1929, 1937
    - Articles clipped from magazines, re McGuffey:
      - Life, 1913 "
        From the Twenty-first Reader" by Will Vawter (1 page)
      - Saturday Evening Post, That Guy McGuffey" by Hugh S. Fullerton., Nov. 26, 1947. "; (5 pages)
      - Early American and Pioneer Life, Life Story...", Nov. 1934 "; (1 page)
      - The Collector's Journal McGuffey Collections" by Olive Mourvan., 1934. "; (1 page)
      - Life, McGuffey Picnic.", July 20, 1942. "; (2 pages)
    - Ad clipped from magazine (Life?) "After McGuffey"
    - 8 Newspaper clippings re: McGuffey.
      (Items which follow do not refer to McGuffey.)
      - 5 Newspaper clippings on various subjects.
      - 3 engraved illustrations of children and parents.
      - Cover (?) illustration of George Cruikshank Magazine.
      - 2 cover illustrations of Royal Academy Students Club Smoking Concert.
        (Lower half of one is missing)
      - Cover (?) lettered "A colour Poem." etc., (torn in two)
  - "Olive's Dolls", Item 8 (Box 6)
    Cardboard folder with brown paper cover marked in pencil "Olive's Dolls" containing 7 paper dolls about 4.5 cm. Cover 23 × 13.5 cm.
  - [Decorated paper], Item 9 (Box 6)
    Thin paper, trapezoid shaped, decorated with cut and pasted paper; on inside a lady in a rose-colored dress on a silver background, with a large red heart in her hand; on the outside a printed blue house on white, and a pink heart with two white dots. Folded. 8 × 12 cm.
    [missing as of 6-28-1982]
  - Notes written to Mrs. Wright by OP., Item 10 (Box 6)
    - 1. Leslie Stephens
      Note written on small white paper, in ink, re Leslie Stephens.
    - 2. [Decorated paper]
      Small thick white paper with decorative cut-out at top, with note, in ink: "This was made of a very old Wedding Cravat."
    - 3. [Jane Wright]
      Scrap of wrapping paper, noted, ink: "This very (?)/attractive parcel/is for/Jane Wright, et al."
    - 4. [Jane Wright]
      Scrap of white paper noted, ink: "Made for Jane/from sample picked/up on Bullock's floor/& stuffed with blossoms from my little potted/Kumquat Tree."
    - 5. [Jane Wright]
      Scrap of white paper noted, ink: "For Jane" "When Jane makes tea,/here is her teapot/tile & a holder made/from homespun blanket/of 1830-" (pink paper strip attached).
    - 6. ["Mrs. Wright,"]
      Flower shaped cut-out of blue paper noted "Mrs. Wright," ink.
    - 7. [Decorated paper]
      Flower shaped double fold of white paper noted "When you have beef - Even Hamburger!" on outside, and "Rosemary" inside.
    - 8. [Jane Wright]
      Flower shaped cut-out of blue paper noted, in ink, "For G. V./& Jane Wright." one side, and "Seed-Cakes/like my/New England/Grandmother/used to make/for little Me."
    - 9. [Jane Wright]
      Folder with colored print of Rheims Cathedral on front, with "Jane" in ink at bottom; inside, in ink: "When Jane eats in her Patio/from these flowery plates,/will she please love & think of/The Giver?" In ink below [Mrs. Wright's hand]: "I always Love and think of/the Giver."
  - "To/dearest Jane Wright.", Item 11 (Box 6)
    White envelope addressed, Ink, by OP: "To/dearest Jane Wright." Bears red seal on back, impressed relief of three sailing vessels.
  - Boxes, Item 12 (Box 6)
    - 1. Small candy box
      Small candy box noted in ink by OP: "Nuts fr. our old Woods-/Done up badly, hastily/as someone waits to mail it-"
    - 2. Box
      Box (17.5 × 13.5 cm) decorated on top with paper cut and pasted to form potted flowering plant (Japanese in design) with black scalloped circle at upper right holding perched green bird, and enclosing "Jane" made up of inked dots. Inside cover decorated with hearts, and noted: "For Jane/O.P.fecit."
    - 3. Large flat box
      Large flat box (38 × 18 cm) decorated with paper cut and pasted to form conventionalized flower arrangement in pot.
      [too large for box]
  - Spice bag, Item 13 (Box 6)